TONY: Been a while
since I was up here in front of you.
Maybe I'll do us all a favor
and just stick to the cards.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
There's been speculation that I was
involved in the events that occurred
on the freeway and the rooftop...
CHRISTINE: Sorry, Mr. Stark, do you
honestly expect us to believe that
that was a bodyguard
in a suit that conveniently appeared,
despite the fact that you
sorely despise bodyguards?
TONY: Yes.
CHRISTINE: And this mysterious
bodyguard was somehow equipped
with an undisclosed
Stark high-tech powered battle...
TONY: I know that it's confusing.
It is one thing to question the official
story, and another thing entirely
to make wild accusations,
or insinuate that I'm a superhero.
I mean, let's face it,
I'm not the heroic type.
(MAN TRANSLATING
SIMULTANEOUSLY IN RUSSIAN)
A laundry list
of character defects,
all the mistakes I've made,
largely public.
The truth is
I am Iron Man.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(ANTON CALLING OUT WEAKLY)
Ivan.
Vanya.
(ANTON COUGHING)
(ANTON GASPING)
(TV ANNOUNCER CHATTERING
IN RUSSIAN)
(IN RUSSIAN)
(ANTON COUGHS)
(ANTON EXHALES)
(ROARING)
(POWER SURGING)
(SQUAWKS)
(CHUCKLING)
MAN: (ON RADIO) 270 at 30 knots.
Holding steady at 15,000 feet.
You are clear for exfiltration
over the drop zone.
(SHOOT TO THRILL PLAYING)
Subtitle | www.movieddl.me
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SHOOT TO THRILL PLAYING
IN THE STADIUM)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SONG ENDS)
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Tony! Tony! Tony! Tony!
Oh! It's good to be back.
- You missed me?
- MAN: Blow something up!
I missed you, too.
Blow something up? I already did that.
(PEOPLE CHUCKLING)
I'm not saying that the world is enjoying
its longest period of uninterrupted peace
in years because of me.
(CROWD CHEERING)
I'm not saying
that from the ashes of captivity,
never has a greater phoenix metaphor
been personified in human history.
I'm not saying that Uncle Sam
can kick back on a lawn chair,
sipping on an iced tea
because I haven't come across anyone
who's man enough
to go toe-to-toe with me on my best day.
(CHEERING LOUDLY)
WOMAN: I love you, Tony!
Please, it's not about me.
It's not about you.
It's not even about us. It's about legacy.
It's about what we choose
to leave behind for future generations.
And that's why for the next year
and for the first time since 1974,
the best and brightest men and women
of nations and corporations
the world over
will pool their resources,
share their collective vision,
to leave behind a brighter future.
- (CHEERING)
- It's not about us.
Therefore, what I'm saying,
if I'm saying anything,
is welcome back to the Stark Expo.
And now, making a special guest
appearance from the great beyond
to tell you what it's all about,
please welcome my father, Howard.
Everything is achievable
through technology.
Better living, robust health,
and for the first time in human history,
the possibility of world peace.
So, from all of us here
at Stark Industries,
I would like to personally introduce you
to the City of the Future.
Technology holds infinite possibilities
for mankind,
and will one day rid society of all its ills.
Soon, technology will affect the way
you live your life every day.
No more tedious work,
leaving more time for leisure activities
and enjoying the sweet life.
The Stark Expo. Welcome.
(CROWD CHEERING)
We are coming to you live
from the kickoff of the Stark Expo,
where Tony Stark
has just walked offstage.
Don't worry
if you can't make it down here tonight
because this Expo goes on all year long.
And I'm gonna be here
checking out all the attractions
and the pavilions and the inventions
from all around the world.
- Make sure you join me...
- All right, it's a zoo out there, watch out.
- Open up, let's go.
- TONY: Hey! Nice to see you.
- All right. Thank you. I remember you.
- WOMAN: Tony, Tony...
- TONY: Hey, hey...
- Call me.
HAPPY: Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Come on, come on.
TONY: Hello. It would be a pleasure.
HAPPY: Okay.
TONY: See you, buddy.
This is Larry.
TONY: Hey, the oracle of Oracle.
What a pleasure. Nice to see you.
Call me. Call me.
HAPPY: Larry King.
TONY: Larry!
Ah, yes, my people, my people.
- Come on, Tony. There we go.
- Very mellow.
- That wasn't so bad.
- No, it was perfect.
Look what we got here, the new model.
TONY: Hey, does she come
with the car?
HAPPY: I certainly hope so.
- Hi.
- MARSHAL: Hi.
- And you are?
- Marshal.
- Irish. I like it.
- Pleased to meet you, Tony.
I'm on the wheel. Do you mind?
Where you from?
- Bedford.
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
- Yeah? You found me.
(TONY CLEARS THROAT)
- What are you up to later?
- Serving subpoenas.
Yikes.
He doesn't like to be handed things.
- Yeah, I have a peeve.
- I got it.
You are hereby ordered to appear
before the Senate
Armed Services Committee
tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.m.
- Can I see a badge?
- You wanna see the badge?
He likes the badge.
- You still like it?
- Yep.
- How far are we from D.C.?
- D.C.? 250 miles.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
STERN: Mr. Stark, could we pick up now
where we left off?
- (BANGING GAVEL)
- Mr. Stark. Please.
-Yes, dear?
- Can I have your attention?
Absolutely.
Do you or do you not possess
a specialized weapon?
-I do not.
- You do not?
I do not. Well, it depends
on how you define the word "weapon."
-The Iron Man weapon.
- My device does not fit that description.
Well... How would you describe it?
I would describe it by defining it
as what it is, Senator.
-As?
- It's a high-tech prosthesis.
(ALL LAUGHING)
That is... That is...
That's actually the most apt description
I can make of it.
It's a weapon. It's a weapon, Mr. Stark.
Please, if your priority was actually
the well-being of the American citizen...
My priority is to get the Iron Man
weapon turned over to the people
-of the United States of America.
- Well, you can forget it.
I am Iron Man. The suit and I are one.
To turn over the Iron Man suit
would be to turn over myself,
which is tantamount
to indentured servitude or prostitution,
depending on what state you're in.
-You can't have it.
- Look, I'm no expert...
In prostitution? Of course not.
You're a senator. Come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm no expert in weapons.
We have somebody here
who is an expert on weapons.
I'd now like to call Justin Hammer,
our current primary weapons contractor.
Let the record reflect that I observed
Mr. Hammer entering the chamber,
and I am wondering
if and when any actual expert
will also be in attendance.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
(LAUGHS)
Absolutely. I'm no expert. I defer
to you, Anthony. You're the wonder boy.
Senator, if I may.
I may well not be an expert,
but you know who was the expert?
Your dad. Howard Stark.
Really a father to us all,
and to the military-industrial age.
Let's just be clear.
He was no flower child. He was a lion.
We all know why we're here.
In the last six months,
Anthony Stark has created a sword
with untold possibilities.
And yet he insists it's a shield.
He asks us to trust him
as we cower behind it.
I wish I were comforted, Anthony,
I really do.
I'd love to leave my door unlocked
when I leave the house,
but this ain't Canada.
You know, we live in a world
of grave threats,
threats that Mr. Stark
will not always be able to foresee.
Thank you.
God bless Iron Man. God bless America.
That is well said, Mr. Hammer.
The committee would now like to invite
Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes
to the chamber.
Rhodey? What?
Hey, buddy.
I didn't expect to see you here.
Look, it's me, I'm here.
Deal with it. Let's move on.
I just...
RHODES: Drop it.
TONY: All right, I'll drop it.
STERN: I have before me a complete
report on the Iron Man weapon,
compiled by Colonel Rhodes.
And, Colonel, for the record,
can you please read page 57,
paragraph four?
You're requesting
that I read specific selections
-from my report, Senator?
- Yes, sir.
It was my understanding
that I was going to be testifying
in a much more comprehensive
and detailed manner.
I understand.
A lot of things have changed today.
-So if you could just read...
- You do understand
that reading a single paragraph
out of context does not reflect
-the summary of my final...
- Just read it, Colonel. I do. Thank you.
Very well.
"As he does not operate within
any definable branch of government,
"Iron Man presents a potential threat
to the security of both the nation
"and to her interests."
I did, however, go on to summarize
that the benefits of iron Man
-far out weigh the liabilities.
- Uh... Uh... Uh...
-And that it would be in our interest...
- That's enough, Colonel.
-...to fold Mr. Stark...
- That's enough.
...into the existing
chain of command, Senator.
I'm not a joiner, but I'll consider
Secretary of Defense, if you ask nice.
- (PEOPLE LAUGHING)
- We can amend the hours a little bit.
I'd like to go on and show, if I may,
the imagery
that's connected to your report.
I believe it is somewhat premature
to reveal these images
- to the general public at this time.
- STERN: With all due respect,
Colonel, I understand.
And if you could just narrate those
for us, we'd be very grateful.
Let's have the images.
Intelligence suggests
that the devices seen in these photos
are, in fact, attempts at making
manned copies of Mr. Stark's suit.
This has been corroborated by our allies
and local intelligence on the ground,
indicating that these suits are quite
possibly, at this moment, operational.
Hold on one second, buddy.
Let me see something here.
Oh! Boy, I'm good.
I commandeered your screens.
I need them.
Time for a little transparency.
-Now, let's see what's really going on.
- What is he doing?
If you will direct your attention
to said screens...
I believe that's North Korea.
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING ON TV)
Can you turn that off? Take it off.
Iran.
(MAN SHOUTING ON TV)
No grave immediate threat here.
Is that Justin Hammer?
How did Hammer get in the game?
TONY: Justin, you're on TV. Focus up.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
HAMMER: Okay, give me a left twist.
Left's good. Turn to the right.
(MAN SCREAMING ON TV)
HAMMER:Oh, shit. Oh, shit!
TONY: Wow.
Yeah, I'd say most countries,
five, 10 years away.
Hammer Industries, 20.
I'd like to point out that
that test pilot survived.
STERN: I think we're done,
is the point that he's making.
(STUTTERS)
I don't think there's any reason...
- The point is, you're welcome, I guess.
- STERN: For what?
Because I'm your nuclear deter rent.
It's working.
We're safe. America is secure.
You want my property?
You can't have it.
But I did you a big favor.
I've successfully privatized world peace.
What more do you want? For now!
I tried to play ball with these ass-clowns.
(BLEEP) you, Mr. Stark.
(BLEEP) you, buddy.
We're adjourned.
We're adjourned for today.
- Okay.
- You've been a delight.
(MAN ON TV
TRANSLATING IN RUSSIAN)
My bond is with the people.
And I will serve this great nation
at the pleasure of myself
If there's one thing I've proven
it's that you can count on me
to pleasure myself
(POWER SURGING)
(SHOULD I STAY OR SHOULD I GO
PLAYING ON STEREO)
Wake up. Daddy's home.
JARVIS: Welcome home, sir.
Congratulations on
the opening ceremonies.
They were such a success,
as was your Senate hearing.
And may I say how refreshing it is
to finally see you in a video
with your clothing on, sir.
(CHUCKLES)
You!
I swear to God I'll dismantle you.
I'll soak your motherboard.
I'll turn you into a wine rack.
(POWERING DOWN)
How many ounces a day of this
gobbledegook am I supposed to drink?
We are up to 80 ounces a day
to counteract the symptoms, sir.
Check palladium levels.
Blood toxicity, 24%.
It appears that the continued use
of the Iron Man suit
is accelerating your condition.
Another core has been depleted.
God, they're running out quick.
I have run simulations
on every known element,
and none can serve as a viable
replacement for the palladium core.
You are running out of both time
and options.
(EXHALES)
Unfortunately, the device that's
keeping you alive is also killing you.
Miss Potts is approaching.
- I recommend that you inform her...
- TONY: Mute.
- Uh-uh.
- Is this a joke?
- What are you thinking?
- What?
- (ANGRILY) What are you thinking?
- Hey, I'm thinking I'm busy.
And you're angry about something.
Do you have the sniffles?
I don't wanna get sick.
- Did you just donate...
- Keep your business.
...our entire modern art collection
to the...
- Boy Scouts of America.
- ...Boy Scouts of America?
Yes. It is a worthwhile organization.
I didn't physically check the crates
but, basically, yes.
And it's not "our" collection,
it's my collection. No offense.
No, you know what?
I think I'm actually entitled
to say "our" collection
considering the time that I put in,
over 10 years,
- curating that.
- It was a tax write-off. I needed that.
You know,
there's only about 8,011 things
- that I really need to talk to you about.
- Dummy. Hey, stop spacing out.
The Bridgeport's
already machining that part.
The Expo is a gigantic waste of time.
I need you to wear a surgical mask
until you're feeling better.
- Is that okay?
- That's rude.
There's nothing more important to me
than the Expo.
It's my primary point of concern.
- I don't know why you're...
- The Expo is your ego gone crazy.
Wow. Look at that.
That's modern art. That's going up.
- Oh, you've got to be kidding.
- I'm gonna put this up right now.
- This is vital.
- Stark is in complete disarray.
- You understand that?
- No. Our stocks have never been higher.
- Yes, from a managerial standpoint.
- You are... Well, if it's messy,
- then let's double back.
- Let me give you an example.
- Let's move on to another subject.
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
You are not taking down
the Barnett Newman
- and hanging that up!
- I'm not taking it down.
I'm just replacing it with this.
- Let's see what I can get going here.
- Okay, fine.
My point is,
we have already awarded contracts
- to the wind farm people.
- Yeah. Don't say "wind farm."
- I'm already feeling gassy.
- And to the plastic plantation tree,
which was your idea, by the way.
Those people are on payroll...
- Everything was my idea.
- ...and you won't make a decision.
I don't care
about the liberal agenda anymore.
It's boring. Boring.
I'm giving you a boring alert.
- You do it.
- I do what?
Excellent idea. I just figured this out.
You run the company.
- Yeah, I'm trying to run the company.
- Pepper, I need you to run the company.
- Well, stop trying to do it and do it.
- You will not
- give me the information...
- I'm not asking you to try...
- ...in order to...
- I'm asking you
to physically do it. I need you to do it.
- I am trying to do it.
- Pepper, you're not listening to me!
- No, you are not listening to me.
- I'm trying to make you CEO.
Why won't you let me?
- Have you been drinking?
- Chlorophyll.
I hereby irrevocably appoint you
chairman and CEO of Stark Industries,
effective immediately.
Yeah, done deal. Okay?
I've actually given this
a fair amount of thought,
believe it or not.
Doing a bit of headhunting, so to speak,
trying to figure out
who a worthy successor would be.
And then I realized
it's you. It's always been you.
I thought there'd be a legal issue,
but actually I'm capable
of appointing my successor.
My successor being you.
Congratulations?
- Take it, just take it.
- I don't know what to think.
Don't think. Drink.
- (LAUGHING IN SHOCK)
- There you go.
(MAN SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
(TONY CHATTERING)
PEPPER: The notary's here!
Can you please come
sign the transfer paperwork?
TONY: I'm on happy time.
(GROANS)
- Sorry.
- What the hell was that?
It's called mixed martial arts.
It's been around for three weeks.
It's called dirty boxing.
There's nothing new about it.
TONY: All right, put them up. Come on.
I promise you this is the only time
I will ask you to sign over your company.
I need you to initial each box.
Lesson one. Never take your eye off...
(GRUNTING)
(BELL RINGS)
HAPPY: That's it. I'm done.
- What's your name, lady?
- Rushman. Natalie Rushman.
Front and center. Come into the church.
No. You're seriously not gonna ask...
TONY: If it pleases the court,
which it does.
- It's no problem.
- I'm sorry. He's very eccentric.
What?
- Can you give her a lesson?
- No problem.
(WHISPERING) Pepper.
What?
- Who is she?
- She is from legal.
And she is potentially a very expensive
sexual harassment lawsuit
- if you keep ogling her like that.
- I need a new assistant, boss.
Yes, and I've got
three excellent potential candidates.
They're lined up and ready to meet you.
I don't have time to meet.
I need someone now. I feel like it's her.
No, it's not.
- You ever boxed before?
- I have, yes.
What, like, the Tae Bo? Booty Boot
Camp? Crunch? Something like that?
(CLEARS THROAT)
- How do I spell your name, Natalie?
- R-U-S-H-M-A-N.
PEPPER: What,
are you gonna Google her now?
Hmm? I thought I was ogling her.
Oh, wow.
Very, very impressive individual.
PEPPER: You're so predictable,
you know that?
She's fluent in French, Italian,
Russian, Latin.
- Who speaks Latin?
- No one speaks Latin.
- It's a dead language.
- No one speaks Latin?
You can read Latin
or you can write Latin,
- but you can't speak Latin...
- Did you model in Tokyo?
- 'Cause she modeled in Tokyo.
- Well...
TONY: I need her.
She's got everything that I need.
Rule number one,
never take your eye off your opponent.
(CRACKING)
- Oh, my God!
- Whoa!
- (GRUNTING HAPPILY)
- PEPPER: Happy!
- TONY: That's what I'm talking about.
- I just slipped.
- TONY: You did?
- Yeah.
- (RINGING BELL)
- Looks like a TKO to me.
Just... I need your impression.
You have a quiet reserve.
I don't know, you have an old soul.
- I meant your fingerprint.
- Right.
(TONY CLEARS THROAT)
- So, how are we doing?
- Great. Just wrapping up. Hey.
- You're the boss.
- Will that be all, Mr. Stark?
- No.
- Yes, that will be all, Ms. Rushman.
Thank you very much.
- I want one.
- No.
(TV ANNOUNCER SPEAKING FRENCH)
You know, it's Europe.
Whatever happens the next 20 minutes,
- just go with it.
- Go with it? Go with what?
- NATALIE: Mr. Stark?
- Hey.
Hello. How was your flight?
It was excellent.
Boy, it's nice to see you.
We have one photographer
from the ACM, if you don't mind.
- Okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
- When did this happen?
- What? You made me do it.
- I made you do what?
- You quit. Smile. Look right there.
Stop acting constipated.
- Don't flare your nostrils.
- You are so predictable.
- That's the amazing thing.
- NATALIE: Right this way.
- You look fantastic.
- Why, thank you very much.
But that's unprofessional.
What's on the docket?
You have a 9:30 dinner.
- Perfect. I'll be there at 11 :00.
- Absolutely.
- Is this us?
- It can be.
- Great. Make it us.
- Okay.
- Mr. Musk. How are you?
- Hi, Pepper.
- Congratulations on the promotion.
- Thank you very much.
Elon, how's it going?
Those Merlin engines are fantastic.
Thank you. Yeah, I've got an idea
for an electric jet.
- You do?
- Yeah.
Then we'll make it work.
- You want a massage?
- (SIGHING) Oh, God.
- No, I don't want a massage.
- I'll have Natalie make an...
- I don't want Natalie to do...
- Don't want you tense.
By the way, I didn't mean
to spring this on you.
PEPPER: Thank you very much.
- Green is not your best color.
- PEPPER: Oh, please.
Anthony! Is that you?
- Hey, pal.
- My least favorite person on Earth.
- Justin Hammer.
- How you doing?
You're not the only rich guy here
with a fancy car.
You know Christine Everhart
from Vanity Fair.
- You guys know each other?
- Hi.
- CHRISTINE: Yes.
- Yes!
- Yes, roughly.
- CHRISTINE: We do.
BTW, big story. The new CEO
of Stark Industries. Congratulations.
I know. I know. My editor will kill me
if I don't grab a quote
for our Powerful Women issue.
- Can I?
- Oh! Sure.
She's actually doing a big spread on me
for Vanity Fair.
- I thought I'd throw her a bone, you know.
- Right.
HAMMER: Right?
CHRISTINE: Yes.
Well, she did quite a spread
on Tony last year.
And she wrote a story as well.
PEPPER: It was very impressive.
TONY: That was good.
- PEPPER: Very well done.
- Thank you.
- I'm gonna go wash.
- Don't leave me.
- Hey, buddy. How you doing?
- I'm all right.
- Looking gorgeous.
- Please, this is tough.
- Can I ask you... Is this the first time...
- Fromage.
- Say, "Brie."
- ...that you guys have seen each other?
God, that's so awful. (LAUGHS)
Listen, is it the first time you've seen
each other since the Senate?
Since he got his contract revoked...
- Actually, it's on hold.
- ...when you were attempting to...
That's not what I heard.
What's the difference between "hold"
- and "canceled"? The truth?
- Yes, what is?
No. The truth is...
Why don't we put that away?
The truth is, I'm actually hoping
to present something at your Expo.
Well, if you invent something that works,
I'll make sure I get you a slot.
- Mr. Stark, your corner table is ready.
- Yes?
I actually have a slot this year. Yes, I do.
Hammer needs a slot, Christine.
HAMMER: (LAUGHS AWKWARDLY)
We kid, yeah.
We kid. We're kidders.
(SIGHS)
Got any other bad ideas?
(FANS CLAMORING)
(RACING CAR ENGINES REVVING)
MAN: Tony!
Tony and I... Tony... I love Tony Stark.
Tony loves me. We're not competitors.
Him being out of the picture
created tremendous opportunities
for Hammer Industries, you know?
(STUTTERING)
- Everything that Tony and I do...
- Well, what's the use of having...
- ...is a healthy...
- ...and owning a race car...
- ...competition.
- ...if you don't drive it?
(FANS CHEERING)
Is he driving?
(TV ANNOUNCER SPEAKING FRENCH)
Natalie. Natalie!
- Yes, Miss Potts?
- Did you know about this?
This is the first that I have known of it.
PEPPER: (SIGHS)
This... This cannot happen.
NATALIE: Absolutely. I understand.
How can I help you?
- Where's Happy?
- He's waiting outside.
- Okay, get him. I need Happy.
- Right away.
Tony's... You know, he...
We're not competitive.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You know,
- can you excuse me just one second?
- Just read me what you wrote.
- I will. I will, after.
- Just read it back to me.
But I have to make one quick phone call.
- Where are you going?
- This is great.
- I've got some caviar coming.
- This is great stuff.
- I'll be right back.
- WOMAN: Look!
MAN: That's Stark.
(ENGINES REVVING)
(REVVING ENGINE)
(RACE COMMENTATOR
CHATTERING OVER TANNOY)
(WOMAN ON TV CHATTERING
IN FRENCH)
(POWERING UP)
(MALE TV COMMENTATOR
EXCLAIMING IN FRENCH)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
- Go, go!
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
Hang on.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING IN ALARM)
(TIRES SCREECH)
- Give me the case.
- Here. Take it.
- Where's the key?
- It's in my pocket.
PEPPER: Car!
(GROANS)
PEPPER: Oh, my God!
(CAR HORN BLARING)
- HAPPY: Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Were you heading for me or him?
- I was trying to scare him.
- 'Cause I can't tell!
- Are you out of your mind?
- Better security.
- Get in the car right now!
I was attacked! We need better security.
Get in the car!
TONY: You're CEO. Better security
measures. God, it's embarrassing.
First vacation in two years.
(PEPPER AND HAPPY SCREAMING)
PEPPER: Oh, my God!
- I got him!
- TONY: Hit him again. Hit him again.
Football.
- I got him!
- Take the case! Take it!
- Take the case!
- HAPPY: Give him the case!
PEPPER: Stop banging the car!
(PEPPER SCREAMING)
TONY: Calm down.
God! God!
Give me the case! Please! Come on!
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTING)
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(LAUGHS) You...
(IN RUSSIAN ACCENT) You lose.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
You lose. You lose, Stark.
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Pretty decent tech.
Cycles per second were a little low.
You could have doubled up
your rotations.
You focused the repulsor energy
through ionized plasma channels.
It's effective. Not very efficient.
But it's a passable knock-off.
I don't get it. A little fine tuning,
you could have made a solid paycheck.
You could have sold it
to North Korea, China, Iran,
or gone right to the black market.
You look like you got friends
in low places.
You come from a family
of thieves and butchers.
And now, like all guilty men,
you try to rewrite your own history.
And you forget all the lives
the Stark family has destroyed.
Speaking of thieves,
where did you get this design?
My father. Anton Vanko.
Well, I never heard of him.
My father is the reason you're alive.
The reason I'm alive is 'cause
you had a shot, you took it, you missed.
Did I?
If you can make God bleed,
the people will cease to believe in him.
And there will be blood in the water.
And the sharks will come.
The truth,
all I have to do is sit here and watch
as the world will consume you.
Where will you be watching
the world consume me from?
That's right. A prison cell.
I'll send you a bar of soap.
Hey, Tony. Before you go,
palladium in the chest,
painful way to die.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
It's just unbelievable. It proves
that the genie is out of the bottle
and this man has no idea
what he's doing.
He thinks of the Iron Man weapon
as a toy.
I was at a hearing
where Mr. Stark, in fact, was adamant
that these suits
can't exist anywhere else,
don't exist anywhere else,
never will exist anywhere else,
at least for five to 10 years,
and here we are in Monaco realizing,
"Uh-oh. These suits exist now."
TONY: Mute.
He should be giving me a medal.
That's the truth.
- What is that?
- This is your in-flight meal.
Did you just make that?
Yeah. Where do you think I've been
for three hours?
Tony,
what are you not telling me?
I don't want to go home.
At all.
Let's cancel my birthday party and...
We're in Europe.
Let's go to Venice, Cipriani.
- Remember?
- Oh, yes.
It's a great place to
- be healthy.
- I don't think this is the right time.
We're in kind of a mess.
Yeah, but maybe that's why
it's the best time.
- 'Cause then we...
- Well, I think as the CEO,
I need to show up.
As CEO, you are entitled to a leave.
- A leave?
- A company retreat.
- A retreat? During a time like this?
- Just a ride.
Well, I'm just saying, to recharge
our batteries and figure it all out.
Not everybody runs on batteries, Tony.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(TIMER BEEPING)
(ORDERING IN FRENCH)
(QUESTIONING IN FRENCH)
(NECK SNAPPING)
(SIREN BLARING)
(GUARDS SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
(SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
(SOFT CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, there he is. There he is.
What an absolute pleasure. Welcome.
Oh, goodness gracious. Can we get
the handcuffs off my friend here?
Forgive me, I'm sorry.
I'm such a huge fan of yours.
I didn't want to make
a first impression like this.
He's not an animal. Come on.
He's a human being. Thank you.
(GUARD AND HAMMER
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(DISMISSIVELY) Oui, oui.
We're fine.
My name is Justin Hammer.
I'd like to do some business with you.
Please sit.
Dig in. What do we have today, Jack?
- We have some salmon carpaccio.
- HAMMER: Salmon carpaccio.
Mmm-mmm.
Anything you want here, we got it.
I like my dessert first.
I had this flown in from San Francisco.
It's Italian, though.
Organic ice cream.
I got a sweet tooth.
Apparently you do, too, for Tony Stark.
What I saw you do to Tony Stark
on that track,
how you stepped up to him
in front of God and everybody,
that was... Wow!
You spoke to me with what you did.
And I know that you knew
that I'd be listening.
This is why I couldn't bear to have you
shipped off to God knows where.
It would have been
such a waste of talent.
But if I might make a suggestion,
you know,
you don't just go and try and kill the guy.
I think, if I may, you go after his legacy.
That's what you kill.
You and me,
we are a lot alike in a lot of ways.
The only difference between you and I
is that I have resources.
I think, if I may,
you need my resources.
Someone behind you, a benefactor.
I'd like to be that guy.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Okay. Do you speak English?
Because I can get a translator.
I don't know. Have you been
understanding everything I'm saying?
Very good, man.
- (LAUGHING) Very good, man.
Hey! Huh?
- Hey.
- Yes?
I want my bird.
- A bird? You want a bird?
- I want my bird.
I can get you a bird.
I can get you 10 birds.
- (POUNDS TABLE)
- I want my bird.
Well, okay. Nothing's impossible.
I could...
Are we talking about...
Is this a bird back in Russia?
Yes, but the fundamentals
of the company are still very, very strong
- despite the events in Monaco.
- Yes, of course.
- The AP wants a quote.
- (WHISPERS) Don't tell him. Fax them...
Where is he?
- He doesn't want to be disturbed.
- He's downstairs.
- ...what happened in Monaco?
- PEPPER: Yes, but...
But his continuing erratic behavior
may lead many people
to ask themselves,
"Can this man still protect us?"
PEPPER: Iron Man never stopped
protecting us.
The events in Monaco proved that.
JARVIS: Query complete, sir.
Anton Vanko was a Soviet physicist
who defected to the United States
in 1963.
However, he was accused of espionage
and was deported in 1967.
His son, Ivan, who is also a physicist,
was convicted of selling Soviet-era
weapons-grade plutonium to Pakistan,
and served 15 years in Kopeisk prison.
No further records exist.
Tony, you gotta get upstairs
and get on top
of this situation right now.
Listen. I've been on the phone
with the National Guard all day,
trying to talk them out
of rolling tanks up the PCH,
knocking down your front door
and taking these.
They're gonna take your suits, Tony,
okay? They're sick of the games.
You said nobody else would possess
this technology for 20 years.
Well, guess what?
Somebody else had it yesterday.
It's not theoretical anymore.
Are you listening to me?
- Are you okay?
- (GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Let's go.
- (TONY GASPS)
- Hey, man.
Hey, hey!
- You all right?
- Yeah, I should get to my desk.
(GASPS)
- See that cigar box?
- Yeah.
It's palladium.
(TONY GROANING)
- Is that supposed to be smoking?
- If you must know, it's neutron damage.
It's from the reactor wall.
You had this in your body?
And how about the high-tech
crossword puzzle on your neck?
Road rash.
Thank you.
(TONY SIGHING)
- What are you looking at?
- I'm looking at you.
You wanna do
this whole lone gunslinger act
and it's unnecessary.
You don't have to do this alone.
You know, I wish I could believe that.
I really do. But you've gotta trust me.
Contrary to popular belief,
I know exactly what I'm doing.
(SNORTS SOFTLY)
HAMMER:This is where we do it.
This is my humble abode.
You can work in absolute peace.
Must be fun to be dead, right?
No pressure.
Here they are. I'm very excited.
They're combat-ready.
I may have done a few miscalculations
and rushed the prototype
into production.
(CHUCKLING) Sue me, I'm enthusiastic.
Go ahead, take a look around.
(STAMMERING) Oh,
you don't wanna do that.
You'll be able to access that
as soon as we generate
some encrypted pass codes.
Can we generate
some encrypted pass codes?
Get some of those
encrypted pass codes, Jack.
Never mind, I...
Wow. Okay. Good stuff.
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
- Sorry?
- Software shit.
Uh-huh?
Well... (LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
You're good. You really blasted in
past the firewall there. Uh...
Let me show you where
you're gonna be working primarily.
Go ahead, take a look.
Get a good look at that.
That's something, isn't it?
You know,
those are really just for show and tell.
They're $125.7 million a pop, so...
Wait! Oh, gosh. Uh...
(WHISPERS) Jesus Christ.
Get somebody up here.
Um, that's where the pilot goes.
I'm having a tough time
finding volunteers. (LAUGHS)
I'll take care of that, just leave it.
What you want them do?
Well, long term, I want them to put me
in the Pentagon for the next 25 years.
I want to make Iron Man
look like an antique.
I wanna go to that Stark Expo,
I wanna take a dump
in Tony's front yard.
You know what I'm talking about?
- (CHUCKLES) I can do that. No problem.
- Yeah?
Hey, fabulous! I love it.
Hey, this is our guy. Didn't I tell you?
I had a feeling.
Do you know which watch
you'd like to wear tonight, Mr. Stark?
I'll give them a look.
I should cancel the party, huh?
- Probably.
- Yeah. Cause it's, um...
- III-timed.
- Right, sends the wrong message.
Inappropriate.
Is that dirty enough for you?
Gold face, brown band.
The Jaeger. I'll give that a look.
Bring them over here.
I'll take that. Why don't you...
I gotta say it.
It's hard to get a read on you.
- Where are you from?
- Legal.
Can I ask you a question,
hypothetically?
Bit odd.
If this was your last birthday party
you were ever gonna have,
how would you celebrate it?
I'd do whatever I wanted to do
with whoever I wanted to do it with.
(SIGHING)
(SCRATCHING)
(CALIFORNIA LOVE PLAYING)
VALET: Good evening.
MAN: Good evening.
Yes, sir, I understand.
No. No, sir, that will not be necessary.
I'll handle it.
Sir, I personally guarantee
that within 24 hours,
Iron Man will be back on watch.
Hey, Pepper.
- I'm... I'm going to go get some air.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know what to do.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- (PEOPLE WHOOPING)
- (CRASHING)
(TONY LAUGHING DRUNKENLY)
- That's it. I'm making...
- No, no, no. Don't call anyone.
Pepper. This is ridiculous.
I just stuck my neck out for this guy.
I know. I know. I get it.
I'm gonna handle it, okay?
Just let me handle it.
Handle it. Or I'm gonna have to.
You know, the question
I get asked most often is,
"Tony, how do you go to the bathroom
in the suit?"
Just like that.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(TONY GIGGLING DRUNKENLY)
Does this guy know
how to throw a party or what?
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
I love you.
Unbelievable! Thank you so much.
Tony, we all thank you so much
for such a wonderful night.
And we're gonna say good night now,
- (GUESTS GROANING)
- and thank you all for coming.
No, no, no, we can't... Wait, wait, wait.
We didn't have the cake.
We didn't blow out the candles.
You're out of control, okay?
Trust me on this one, okay?
- You're out of control, gorgeous.
- It's time to go to bed. It's time.
- Give me another smooch.
- You're not going to be
- happy about this.
- Come on, you know you want to.
(ENUNCIATING) You just peed the suit.
- I know. It has a filtration system.
- It's not sexy.
You could drink that water.
Just send everybody home, okay?
It's time to...
- If you say so.
- Okay.
I'll take this, you take that.
Pepper Potts.
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
She's right. The party's over.
Then again, the party was over for me,
like, an hour and a half ago.
The after-party starts in 15 minutes!
(GUESTS CHEERING WILDLY)
And if anybody, Pepper,
doesn't like it, there's the door.
(ENERGY BOLT FIRES)
Yeah!
Hit!
Pull!
(TONY EXCLAIMING)
(TONY CHEERING)
TONY: I think she wants the Gallagher!
RHODES: I'm only gonna say this once.
Get out.
You don't deserve to wear one of these.
Shut it down!
Goldstein.
Yes, Mr. Stark?
(GIGGLING) Give me a phat beat
to beat my buddy's ass to.
(ANOTHER ONE BITES THE DUST
PLAYING)
RHODES: I told you to shut it down.
TONY:Now, put that thing back where
you found it before someone gets hurt.
Really?
Sorry, pal,
but Iron Man doesn't have a sidekick.
Sidekick this!
Had enough?
- PEPPER: Natalie!
- Miss Potts.
Don't you "Miss Potts" me! I'm on to you.
You know what?
Ever since you came here...
(SHRIEKS)
HAPPY: Pepper!
Get out of here. Get out of here.
TONY: You want it? Take it!
(MUSIC STOPS)
(ROARS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
RHODES: Put your hand down.
You think you got what it takes
to wear that suit?
RHODES:
We don't have to do this, Tony.
You wanna be the War Machine,
take your shot.
- Put it down!
- You gonna take a shot?
- No!
- Drop it, Tony!
- Take it!
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(BEEPING)
(SYSTEMS POWERING UP)
(ON RADIO) Edwards Tower, this is
Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes,
inbound from three miles east
at 5,000 feet...
(MEN CHATTERING)
(RUMBLING APPROACHING)
(WINDOWS RATTLING)
- Colonel.
- Major.
Wow.
Yeah.
Let's take it inside.
MAJOR: Clear the area.
Sir! I'm gonna have to ask you
to exit the donut.
I told you I don't wanna join
your super-secret boy band.
(CHUCKLES) No, no, no. See,
I remember, you do everything yourself.
- How's that working out for you?
- It's... It's... It's...
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
I don't wanna get off on the wrong foot.
Do I look at the patch or the eye?
Honestly, I'm a bit hung over.
I'm not sure if you're real
or if I'm having...
I am very real.
I'm the realest person
you're ever gonna meet.
- Just my luck. Where's the staff here?
- That's not looking so good.
TONY: I've been worse.
NATALIE: We've secured the perimeter,
but I don't think we should
hold it for too much longer.
TONY: Huh!
- You're...fired.
- That's not up to you.
Tony, I want you to meet
Agent Romanoff.
- Hi.
- I'm a S.H.I.E.L.D. shadow.
Once we knew you were ill,
I was tasked to you by Director Fury.
I suggest you apologize.
You've been very busy.
You made your girl your CEO,
you're giving away all your stuff.
You let your friend
fly away with your suit.
Now, if I didn't know better...
You don't know better.
I didn't give it to him. He took it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. He took it?
You're Iron Man and he just took it?
The little brother walked in there,
kicked your ass and took your suit?
Is that possible?
Well, according to Mr. Stark's
database security guidelines,
there are redundancies
to prevent unauthorized usage.
(SNORTS SOFTLY)
- What do you want from me?
- What do we want from you? Uh-uh.
(STRESSING) What do you
want from me?
You have become a problem,
a problem I have to deal with.
Contrary to your belief,
you are not the center of my universe.
I have bigger problems than you
in the southwest region to deal with.
Hit him.
(GROANS) Oh, God, are you gonna
steal my kidney and sell it?
Could you please not do anything awful
for five seconds?
- What did she just do to me?
- What did we just do for you?
That's lithium dioxide.
It's gonna take the edge off.
We're trying to get you back to work.
Give me a couple of boxes of that.
I'll be right as rain.
It's not a cure,
it just abates the symptoms.
Doesn't look like it's gonna be
an easy fix.
Trust me, I know. I'm good at this stuff.
I've been looking for a suitable
replacement for palladium.
I've tried every combination, every
permutation of every known element.
Well, I'm here to tell you,
you haven't tried them all.
Hey, hey, hey. Special delivery.
Candygram.
HAMMER: I brought you something.
Oh, yeah.
- (BIRD SQUAWKS)
- (HAMMER CHUCKLING)
We got you the bird, pal!
This is not my bird.
What do you mean? That's the bird.
This is the bird. Yeah!
Pulled a lot of strings to get this bird.
This is a great bird.
- It's a beautiful bird.
- We got this all the way from Russia.
- (POUNDS TABLE)
- Hey, man, this not my bird.
Well, listen, even if it's not the bird,
I mean, this is a gorgeous bird.
I mean, you know, look, don't get
so attached to things. Learn to let go.
(BIRD SQUAWKS)
Wait a minute. Jack, what is that?
Is that... That's not a helmet.
What is that?
Um...
Ivan... What's this? Jack.
Is that a helmet?
It doesn't look like a helmet to me.
How... How are you supposed
to get a head in there?
- Jack, could you put your head in there?
- No.
Try to put your head in there.
Go ahead. Try to put your head in there.
See, Ivan?
He can't put his head in there. That's...
That's not a helmet. It's a head.
I need to put a guy in there.
I need to fit a person in that suit.
You understand?
- Drone better.
- What? Drone better?
Why is drone better?
People make problem.
Trust me. Drone better.
Ivan, you know, I like you.
I got you the bird.
You said, "No problem."
That's what you said to me.
Now I need suits.
The government wants suits.
Like Iron Man. You understand?
That's what the people want.
That's what's gonna make them happy.
Hey, man.
Don't get too attached to things.
Learn to let go.
These drones
better steal the show, Ivan.
You understand?
Better rock my world, Ivan.
Unbelievable.
This ought to get the Senate off my ass.
- It's functional?
- Fully mission-capable.
Good. Get Hammer down here
to weaponize it.
Sir?
Justin Hammer's making
a weapons presentation at the Expo.
We'd like this to introduce it.
Sir, I don't believe that the Expo...
Colonel, the world needs
to see this fast.
- We've got to make this happen.
- Yes, General, but...
It's also an order.
Yes, sir.
Good work, Colonel.
You've made your country proud.
Thank you, sir.
That thing in your chest
is based on unfinished technology.
No, it was finished.
It has never been particularly effective
- until I miniaturized it and put it in my...
- No. Howard said the arc reactor
was the stepping stone
to something greater.
He was about to kick off an energy race
that was gonna dwarf the arms race.
He was on to something big,
something so big
that it was gonna make
the nuclear reactor
look like a triple-A battery.
Just him,
or was Anton Vanko in on this, too?
Anton Vanko
is the other side of that coin.
Anton saw it as a way to get rich.
When your father found out,
he had him deported.
When the Russians found out
he couldn't deliver,
they shipped his ass off to Siberia
and he spent the next 20 years
in a vodka-fuel led rage.
Not quite the environment
you want to raise a kid in,
the son you had the misfortune
of crossing paths with in Monaco.
You told me I hadn't tried everything.
What do you mean I haven't
tried everything? What haven't I tried?
He said that you were the only person
with the means and knowledge
to finish what he started.
- He said that?
- Mmm.
Are you that guy? Hmm? Are you?
'Cause if you are, then you can solve
the riddle of your heart.
I don't know
where you get your information,
but he wasn't my biggest fan.
What do you remember about your dad?
He was cold, he was calculating.
He never told me he loved me.
He never even told me he liked me,
so it's a little tough for me to digest
when you're telling me he said
the whole future was riding on me
and he's passing it down.
I don't get that.
You're talking about a guy
whose happiest day
was when he shipped me off
to boarding school.
That's not true.
Well, then, clearly you knew my dad
better than I did.
As a matter of fact, I did. He was one of
the founding members of S.H.I.E.L.D.
What?
- I got a 2:00.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- What's this?
- Okay, you're good, right?
- No, I'm not good.
- You got this? Right? Right?
Got what? I don't even know
what I'm supposed to get.
Natasha will remain a floater at Stark
with her cover intact.
- You remember Agent Coulson, right?
- Yeah.
Oh, and Tony,
remember, I got my eye on you.
We've disabled all communications.
No contact with the outside world.
Good luck.
Please.
First thing, I need a little bodywork.
I'll put in a little time at the lab.
If we could send one of your goon squad
down to The Coffee Bean,
Cross Creek, for a Starbucks run,
or something like that, that'd be nice.
I'm not here for that.
I've been authorized by Director Fury
to use any means necessary
to keep you on premises.
If you attempt to leave
or play any games,
I will tase you and watch Supernanny
while you drool into the carpet.
- Okay?
- I think I got it, yeah.
Enjoy your evening's entertainment.
- Think this is the power source?
- Major, this is not a scientific exercise.
Let's just focus on arming it, all right?
Yes, sir.
HAMMER: Oh, yes!
Oh, yes, yes, yes. Is it my birthday?
You got it.
What did you do? What did you do?
(SIGHING REVERENTLY) Oh!
- Is this what I think it is?
- Yes, it is.
Hammer, I want to know
what you're gonna do for us.
What am I going to do for you?
Well, the first thing I'm gonna do for you
is I'm gonna upgrade your software.
- And then, second, I think I should...
- That's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about firepower.
Well, you're talking to the right guy.
(CRUNCHING)
Claridge Hi-Tec,
semi-automatic, 9mm pistol.
Too downtown? I agree.
M24 shotgun, pump action.
Five-round magazine.
You know what? You're not a hunter.
What am I talking about?
I'm getting rid of it.
This is the FN-2000 from Belgium.
They do make something
better than waffles.
It's beautiful, but I can tell
this isn't disco enough for you,
so I'm gonna put it right here.
You're looking at
a Milkor 40mm grenade launcher.
Tear gas, smoke. Hippie control.
You're tough.
Let me tell you something.
Size does matter.
Don't let anyone tell you different.
This is an M134 7.62 Minigun.
Six individual barrels.
The torso taker, powder maker.
Our boys in uniform call it
Uncle Gazpacho,
or Puff the Magic Dragon.
Okay.
These are the Cubans, baby.
This is the Cohibas, the Montecristos.
This is a kinetic-kill, side-winder vehicle
with a secondary
cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine RDX burst.
It's capable of busting the bunker
under the bunker you just busted.
If it were any smarter,
it would write a book.
A book that would make Ulysses
look like it was written in crayon.
It would read it to you.
This is my Eiffel Tower.
This is my Rachmaninoff's Third.
My Pietá.
It's completely elegant.
It's bafflingly beautiful.
It's capable of reducing the population
of any standing structure to zero.
I call it the Ex-Wife.
That's the best I got.
Are we gonna do this?
Give me something here.
- You're like a sphinx. I can't read you.
- I think I'll take it.
- Which one?
- All of it.
All of it.
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
Everything is achievable
through technology.
Better living, robust health
and for the first time in human history,
the possibility of world peace.
I'm Howard Stark,
and everything you'll need for the future
can be found right here.
City of the Future?
City of Tomorrow? City of..
I'm Howard Stark,
and everything you'll need in the future
can be found right here.
So, from all of us at Stark Industries,
I would like to personally...
Tony, what are you doing back there?
What is that? Put that back.
(FIRMLY) Put it back
where you got it from.
Where's your mother? Maria?
Go on. Go, go, go, go.
All right, I think we got...
I'll... I'll... I'll come in and...
Are you waiting on me?
So, from all of us at Stark Industries,
I'd like to personally show you
my ass.
I'd like to... I can't... This is...
I can't... We have this, don't we?
This is a ridiculous way...
Everything
is achievable
through technology.
Tony?
You're too young
to understand this right now,
so I thought
I would put it on film for you.
I built this for you.
And someday you'll realize
that it represents a whole lot more
than just people's inventions.
It represents my life's work.
This is the key to the future.
I'm limited by the technology of my time,
but one day you'll figure this out.
And when you do,
you will change the world.
What is and always will be
my greatest creation
is you.
(POWERFUL ENGINE REVVING)
(BOTH SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
- $6. Six.
- I don't have any dough.
- Here.
- No, sir, that's too much.
No, it's fine. Take that.
- It's fine.
- No, señor.
Take it. Take it.
I don't like people handing me things.
If you just drop that there,
that'd be great.
- Are you Iron Man?
- Sometimes.
We believe in you!
It was an illegal seizure
of trademark property.
- Miss Potts?
- TONY: Relax.
SECRETARY: Mr. Stark...
TONY: Is here.
- He refuses...
- I don't. It's fine.
- I'll just be a second.
- Listen, it's our position
that Stark has and continues to maintain
proprietary ownership
of the Mark ll platform.
MAN ON TV: When Mr. Stark announced
he was indeed Iron Man,
- he was making a promise to America.
- PEPPER: No, the suit belongs to us.
We trusted that he would look out for us.
- Yeah, but you're not... Burt...
- He obviously did not.
- And now we learn that his secretary...
- Yes, it does.
...a woman named
Virginia "Pepper" Potts,
has been appointed
as CEO of Stark Industries.
- What are her qualifications?
- (FIRMLY) No.
Ms. Potts is doing nothing
to manage this terrible...
TONY: Mute.
PEPPER: No...
Burt... Burt... Burt, listen to me.
Don't tell me that we have
the best patent lawyers in the country
- and then not let me pursue this.
- I'll get this stuff out of here.
Well, then, tell the President
to sign an order.
(SIGHS) We'll talk about it at the Expo.
Hammer's giving some presentation
tomorrow evening.
- Will Tony Stark be there?
- Will I?
- No, he will not. Bye.
- I would like to be.
- Got a minute?
- No.
Come on, you just got off the phone.
You're fine, 30 seconds.
- Twenty-nine. Twenty-eight.
- Okay, I, um...
I was just driving over here,
and I thought I was coming
to basically apologize, but I'm not.
- Oh, you didn't come here to apologize?
- Look, that goes without saying,
and I'm working on that.
But I haven't been
entirely upfront with you,
and I just want to try to make good.
Can I move this? This is crazy.
It's like a Ferris wheel going.
- I'm trying to get some...
- No.
(TONY CLEARS THROAT)
Do you know how short life is?
And if I never got to express...
And by the way, this is somewhat
revelatory to me. And I don't care...
I mean, I care. It would be nice.
I'm not expecting you to...
Look, here's what I'm trying to say.
I'm just gonna say it.
Let me stop you right here, okay?
Because if you say "I" one more time,
I'm gonna actually hurl something
at your head, I think.
I am trying to run a company.
- Do you have any idea what that entails?
- Yes.
People are relying on you to be Iron Man
and you've disappeared,
and all I'm doing is putting out your fires
and taking the heat for it.
I am trying to do the job
that you were meant to do.
Did you bring me strawberries?
Did you know that there's only
one thing on Earth that I'm allergic to?
Allergic to strawberries. Mmm-hmm.
This is progress, Pepper.
I knew there was a correlation
between you and this.
- I need you...
- I need you, too.
- That's what I'm trying to...
- ...to leave now.
- Ms. Potts?
- Hi, come on in.
- Wheels up in 25 minutes.
- Thank you.
- Anything else, boss?
- I'm good, Hap.
No, I'll be just...another minute.
I lost both the kids in the divorce.
(TONY LAUGHS)
No.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Are you blending in well here, Natalie?
Here at Stark Enterprises?
Your name is Natalie, isn't it?
I thought you two didn't get along.
- No. That's not so.
- It's just me you don't care for.
- No? Nothing?
- PEPPER: Actually, while you're here,
maybe you and Natalie could discuss
the matter of the personal belongings.
Absolutely.
I'm surprised
you can keep your mouth shut.
Boy, you're good. You are mind-blowingly
duplicitous. How do you do it?
You just tear things...
You're a triple impostor.
I've never seen anything like you.
Is there anything real about you?
Do you even speak Latin?
(SPEAKING LATIN)
Which means? Wait. What?
What did you just say?
It means you can either drive yourself
home or I can have you collected.
You're good!
(SIGHS)
(BLOWS)
Jarvis, could you kindly Vac-U-Form
a digital wire frame?
I need a manipulatable projection.
JARVIS: 1974 Stark Expo model scan
complete, sir.
How many buildings are there?
Am I to include
the Belgian waffle stands?
That was rhetorical. Just show me.
Uh-huh. Um...
What does that look like to you, Jarvis?
Not unlike an atom.
In which case the nucleus
would be here.
Highlight the unisphere.
- Lose the footpaths. Get rid of them.
- What is it you're trying to achieve, sir?
I'm discovering... Correction.
I'm rediscovering a new element,
I believe.
Lose the landscaping,
the shrubbery, the trees.
Parking lots, exits, entrances.
Structure the protons and the neutrons
using the pavilions as a framework.
Dad.
Dead for almost 20 years,
and still taking me to school.
The proposed element should serve
as a viable replacement for palladium.
Thanks, Dad.
Unfortunately, it is impossible
to synthesize.
TONY: Uh-huh.
Get ready for a major remodel, fellas!
We're back in hardware mode.
(GRUNTS)
(JACKHAMMER RATTLING)
(RATCHET CLICKING)
- I heard you broke the perimeter.
- Uh, yeah.
That was, like, three years ago.
Where you been?
- I was doing some stuff.
- Yeah, well, me, too, and it worked.
Hey, I'm playing
for the home team, Coulson,
you and all your
Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers.
Now, are you gonna let me work
or break my balls?
What's this doing here?
That's it.
- Bring that to me.
- You know what this is?
It's exactly what I need
to make this work.
Lift the coil.
Go, go. Put your knees into it.
There you go. And...
Drop it. Drop it.
Perfectly level.
- (SNORTS) I'm busy. What do you want?
- Nothing.
- Goodbye. I've been reassigned.
- Huh.
Director Fury wants me in New Mexico.
- Fantastic. Land of Enchantment.
- So I'm told.
- Secret stuff?
- Something like that.
- Good luck.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
- We need you.
- Yeah, more than you know.
- Not that much.
JARVIS: initializing
prismatic accelerator.
(WHIRRING)
Approaching maximum power.
(RUMBLING)
(SCREECHING)
Whoops!
That was easy.
JARVIS: Congratulations, sir.
You have created a new element.
(BEEPING)
Sir, the reactor has accepted
the modified core.
I will begin running diagnostics.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, Ivan.
I got Senator Stern here.
Thought we'd swing over
and look at some of the drone designs.
The drone is not going to be ready.
Not ready? What do you mean?
I can make presentation,
not demonstration.
(LAUGHING) What the hell
is the difference?
Presentation. No fly. No shoot.
Well, wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait. (SIGHS)
What can you make them do? I mean,
this is a weapons demonstration.
- I can make salute.
- You can make salute?
What do you mean, "make salute"?
What the hell does that mean, Ivan?
This is not what we agreed to, okay?
You promised me suits
and then you promised me drones.
- Hey, man, everything will be okay.
- This is not what I wanted.
(PHONE BEEPS)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
Hey, there he is. It's the bird man.
Now you like the bird. Is that right?
Is that your bird? I'm confused.
You said it wasn't,
but now it looks like you're best of pals.
You love that bird, don't you?
You know what? Take the bird.
- (SQUAWKING)
- Hey!
(SQUAWKING)
Take his pillows, too. Both of them.
And his shoes. Take his shoes.
I took your stuff.
How does that make you feel?
Do you feel bad? Good.
(SHOUTING) 'Cause that's how I feel!
We had a contract!
I saved your life
and you give me suits.
That was our deal.
And you did not deliver.
I don't know if you're a genius or a fraud.
I don't know what you are.
Something really, really great
fell into my lap.
And if it hadn't,
I'd be at your mercy tonight.
Now I have a piece of Stark tech
that I pimped out myself.
And now your overpriced paperweights
are gonna look like a backdrop
to my demonstration.
Do you dig what I'm getting at here?
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(CHUCKLING) I don't know
if you know this,
(SHOUTING) but I don't speak Russian!
I'm gonna leave now.
I'm gonna go to the Expo.
Maybe I'll even get laid.
You see these guys?
They're your babysitters.
They are not to be trifled with.
When I get back, we're gonna
renegotiate the terms of our agreement.
And you're gonna make good
on our arrangement
because if you don't,
you're gonna be exactly what you were
when I found you,
a dead man.
You got that?
Maybe you can watch me on TV.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SCOFFS)
TONY: Dummy, you,
can we clean up this mess?
- You're killing me. You know I don't...
- (PHONE RINGING)
JARVIS: incoming call
with a blocked number, sir.
My phone privilege is reinstated. Lovely.
Coulson. How's
the Land of Enchantment?
IVAN: Hey, Tony,
how you doing? (LAUGHS)
- I double cycle.
- You what?
You told me double cycle's more power.
Good advice.
You sound pretty sprightly
for a dead guy.
You, too. (LAUGHS)
- Trace him.
- JARVIS: Sir.
Now, the true history of Stark name
will be written.
Jarvis, where is he?
- Accessing the Oracle grid.
Eastern Seaboard.
What your father did to my family
over 40 years,
I will do to you in 40 minutes.
Sounds good.
Let's get together and hash it out.
JARVIS: Tri-State area.
Manhattan and outlying boroughs.
I hope you're ready.
(DIALING TONE DRONING)
JARVIS: Call trace incomplete.
(SIGHS)
- JARVIS: Sir...
- You want to run some tests, run them.
And assemble the suit while you're at it.
Put it together now.
- We are unclear as to the effects...
- I don't want to hear it, Jarvis.
(COUGHS)
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
That tastes like coconut.
And metal.
Oh, wow, yeah!
(ANNOUNCER CHATTERING OVER PA)
- I'll keep the car down here, all right?
- Thank you, Happy.
ANNOUNCER: ...Justin Hammer.
His presentation will begin shortly
in the main pavilion.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(PICK UP THE PIECES
PLAYING OVER PA)
HAMMER: Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about.
Thanks for coming.
Ladies and gentlemen, for far too long,
this country has had to place its
brave men and women in harm's way,
but then the Iron Man arrived,
and we thought the days of losing lives
were behind us.
Sadly, that technology
was kept out of reach.
That's not fair. That's not right.
- And it's just too bad.
- (SIGHING) Oh, Lord.
Regardless, it was
an impressive innovation,
one that grabbed headlines
the world over.
Well, today, my friends,
the press is faced
with quite a different problem.
They are about to run out of ink.
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
(SOFTLY) Get that out of here.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ladies and gentlemen,
today I present to you
the new face
of the United States military.
The Hammer drone!
(THE CAISSONS GO ROLLING ALONG
PLAYING)
HAMMER: Army!
Navy!
(ANCHORS AWEIGH PLAYING)
(THE U.S. AIR FORCE PLAYING)
Air Force!
Marines!
(THE MARINES' HYMN PLAYING)
HAMMER: Yeah! Yeah! Whoo!
That's a hell of a lot better
than some cheerleaders, let me tell you.
But as revolutionary
as this technology is,
there will always be a need form an
to be present in the theater of war.
Ladies and gentlemen,
today I am proud to present to you
the very first prototype in the
Variable Threat Response Battle Suit
and its pilot, Air Force
Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes.
What?
For America and its allies,
Hammer Industries is reporting for...
(RUMBLING APPROACHING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING LOUDLY)
TONY: We got trouble.
RHODES: Tony,
there are civilians present.
I'm here on orders.
Let's not do this right now.
TONY: Give them a wave.
HAMMER: Hey, all right! Yeah!
TONY: All these people are in danger.
We gotta get them out of here.
You gotta trust me
for the next five minutes.
Yeah, I tried that. I got tossed
around your house, remember?
- Listen, I think he's working with Vanko.
- Vanko's alive?
- HAMMER: Huh? Yeah!
- Where is he?
- What?
- Where's Vanko?
- Who?
- Tell me.
What are you doing here, man?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Is that you?
RHODES: No, I'm not doing that.
That's not me.
I can't move. I'm locked up.
I'm locked up!
Get out of here. Go! This whole
system's been compromised.
TONY: Let's take it outside.
(PEOPLE SHRIEKING)
No. No!
- Jarvis, break in. I need to own him.
- Yes, sir.
Tony, Tony, I'm locked on.
I have target lock.
- On what?
- On you!
Tony, on your six!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- What's going on? What's happening?
- The software's been overridden.
What? What do you mean
it's been overridden?
- What does that mean?
- I think he slaved the drones.
- That's impossible. Call the guards.
- All the phones are down, sir.
HAMMER:
Well, then call their... Call their cells.
Their cell phones
are not working, either, sir.
He's locked us out of the mainframe.
- Who's locked you out of the mainframe?
- Please, please, go away. Go away.
- I've got this handled.
- Have you now?
Yes, I do.
In fact, if your guy hadn't showed up,
this wouldn't be happening.
So please, now go away. Thank you.
Listen, we got to get these bitches
out of here.
- HAMMER: What?
- (NATALIE EXCLAIMS)
You tell me who's behind this.
Who's behind this?
(GROANING) Ivan. Ivan Vanko.
- Where is he?
- He's at my facility.
- I need NYPD, please.
- No, no, no!
- Command Central.
- No, no, honey.
- Don't call the authorities.
- Okay. Right away. Right away.
Step aside. Step aside.
Tell me everything you know. Go.
- How are we doing, Jarvis?
- Remote reboot unsuccessful.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
SECURITY GUARD: This way.
Nobody's answering the phone.
What's going on?
Get in the car.
Take me to Hammer Industries.
- I'm not taking you anywhere.
- Fine. You want me to drive?
No, I'm driving. Get in the car.
Nice work, kid.
RHODES: You got multiples
coming in on you.
Let's get this away from the Expo.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
When we arrive,
I need you to watch the perimeter.
I'm gonna enter the facility
and take down the target.
(CAR HORNS BLARING)
- Watch the road.
- I got it. I got it.
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(MULTIPLE CAR ALARMS BLARING)
Listen, listen. A pack just peeled off.
- They're headed back to the Expo.
- Got it.
RHODES: I'm closing on you.
Ordnance coming in hot, Tony. Watch it.
- NATALIE: Stay in the car.
- I'm not staying in the car.
I said, stay in the car.
What are you wearing?
Look, I'm not letting you
go in there alone.
- (DOOR PANEL BEEPING)
- You want to help? Keep the car running.
Okay.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Hey, hey, hey. You can't come in here.
SECURITY GUARD: Hold on. Hey!
(SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
TECHNICIAN:
Each set of drones is communicating
- in its own unique language.
- Well, choose one and focus on that.
Have you tried Russian?
Why don't you try Russian?
(GRUNTING)
MAN: (OVER RADIO) Attention.
We have intrusion on Grid W.
SECURITY GUARD: We got it.
We're on our way.
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING) I got him!
(GRUNTING)
- Rhodey, you still locked on?
- Yeah.
Drop your socks and grab your Croce.
We're about to get wet on this ride.
Wait, wait, wait!
(GUNS COCKING)
He's gone.
I'm sorry, buddy.
Had to thin out the herd.
What's your 20?
(EXCLAIMING)
- What are you doing?
- I'm rebooting Rhodey's suit.
(GRUNTING)
Tony!
(POWERING DOWN)
(TONY PANTING)
Reboot complete.
You got your best friend back.
- Thank you very much, Agent Romanoff
- Well done with the new chest piece.
I am reading significantly higher output
and your vitals all look promising.
Yes, for the moment, I'm not dying.
Thank you.
What do you mean you're not dying?
Did you just say you're dying?
TONY: Is that you?
No, I'm not. Not anymore.
What's going on?
I was going to tell you.
I didn't want to alarm you.
You were gonna tell me?
You really were dying?
-You didn't let me.
- Why didn't you tell me that?
I was gonna make you an omelet
and tell you.
Hey, hey. Save it for the honeymoon.
You got incoming, Tony.
Looks like the fight's coming to you.
- Great. Pepper?
- PEPPER: Are you okay now?
I am fine. Don't be mad.
-I will formally apologize...
- I am mad!
...when I'm not fending off
a Hammeroid attack.
-Fine.
- We could have been in Venice.
Oh, please.
(DISTORTED) Rhodes?
Snap out of it, buddy. I need you.
They're coming. Come on, let's roll.
- (KNOCKING ON HELMET)
- Get up.
Oh, man. You can have your suit back.
- You okay?
- Yeah, thanks.
- Tony, look, I'm sorry, okay?
- Don't be.
No. I should have trusted you more.
I'm the one who put you in this position.
Forget it.
No. It's your fault.
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
Thank you. That's all I wanted to hear.
Partner.
They're coming in hot, any second.
What's the play?
Well, we want to take
the high ground, okay?
So let's put the biggest gun
up on that ridge.
Got you.
- Where do you want to be?
- Where are you going?
- What're you talking about?
- I meant me.
You have a big gun.
You are not the big gun.
- Tony, don't be jealous.
- No. It's subtle,
- all the bells and whistles.
- Yeah. It's called being a badass.
Fine.
All right.
You go up top. I'll draw them in.
Don't stay down here.
This is the worst place to be.
Okay, you got a spot. Where's mine?
It's the kill box, Tony. Okay?
This is where you go to die.
(ROARING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(WEAPON COCKS)
- See that?
- Yeah, yeah, nice.
TONY: Rhodey?
Get down.
Wow. I think you should lead with that
next time.
Yeah. Sorry, boss.
I can only use it once. It's a one-off.
I told you that five minutes ago.
That's your guy here.
- Excuse me?
- COP: You're being placed under arrest.
- Are you kidding me?
- Hands behind your back, sir.
I'm trying to help here.
HAMMER: (LAUGHS) I get it.
I see what you're doing.
You're trying to pin this on me, huh?
That's good. That's good.
You're starting to think like a CEO,
taking out the competition. I like that.
You think you're making
a problem for me?
I'm gonna make a problem for you.
I'm gonna be seeing you again
real soon.
When they get here,
I think you should station them
at the south, east and both west exits.
COP: We shut down the 7 train
in and out of Willets Point already.
PEPPER: Well, have city buses there
to ferry people to operating lines.
Yeah. Are you coming with us?
- No, I'm gonna stay till the park is clear.
- Okay.
NATALIE: Heads up.
You got one more drone incoming.
This one looks different.
The repulsor signature is
significantly higher.
Good to be back.
RHODES: Oh, this ain't gonna be good.
I got something special for this guy.
I'm gonna bust his bunker
with the Ex-Wife.
TONY: With the what?
(WHIRRING)
(SOFT POP)
- TONY: Hammer tech?
- Yeah.
TONY: I got this.
(GRUNTING)
(TONY BELLOWING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
TONY: Rhodes. I got an idea.
- You want to be a hero?
- What?
I could really use a sidekick.
Put your hand up.
- RHODES: This is your idea?
- Yep.
RHODES: I'm ready. I'm ready!
Go, go, go!
TONY: Take it!
(PANTING)
(WEAKLY) You lose.
(BEEPING)
(BEEPING ACCELERATING)
All these drones are rigged to blow.
We gotta get out of here, man.
Pepper?
(BEEPING)
(PEPPER SCREAMS)
(PEPPER SHRIEKS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, my God! I can't take this anymore.
- You can't? Look at me!
- I can't take this.
My body, literally,
cannot handle the stress.
I never know if you're gonna kill yourself
or wreck the whole company.
I think I did okay.
I quit. I'm resigning.
That's it.
What did you just say? You're done?
That's surprising.
No, it's not surprising. I get it.
- You don't have to make any excuses.
- I'm... I'm... I'm not making any excuses.
You actually were just making excuses.
- But you don't have to.
- No, I wasn't making an excuse.
- I'm actually very justified.
- Listen. Hey, hey.
- You deserve better.
- Well...
You've taken such good care of me.
I've been in a tough spot,
but you got me through it, so...
Right?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Thank you for understanding.
- Yeah, yeah. Let's talk clean-up.
- I'll handle the transition. It'll be smooth.
- Okay. What about the press?
Because you only had the job for a week.
That's gonna seem...
- Well, with you it's like dog years.
- I know.
I mean, it's like the Presidency...
- Weird.
- (SOFTLY) No, it's not weird.
- It's okay, right?
- Yeah.
Run that by me again.
RHODES:I think it was weird.
You guys look like two seals
fighting over a grape.
- I had just quit, actually.
- Yeah, so we're not...
You don't have to do that.
I heard the whole thing.
- You should get lost.
- I was here first. Get a roof.
(TONY CHUCKLES)
- I thought you were out of one-liners.
- That's the last one.
- You kicked ass back there, by the way.
- Thank you. You, too.
Listen, my car got taken out
in the explosion,
so I'm gonna have to hang on
to your suit for a minute, okay?
Not okay. Not okay with that.
It wasn't a question.
How are you gonna resign
if I don't accept?
- (PEPPER LAUGHS)
- Hmm?
I don't think I want you looking at that.
I'm not sure it pertains to you anymore.
Now this, on the other hand,
is Agent Romanoff's assessment of you.
- Read it.
- Uh...
"Personality overview. Mr. Stark displays
compulsive behavior."
In my own defense, that was last week.
"Prone to self-destructive tendencies."
I was dying.
I mean, please. And aren't we all?
"Textbook narcissism"?
Agreed.
Okay, here it is. Uh...
"Recruitment assessment
for Avenger Initiative. Iron Man? Yes."
- I gotta think about it.
- Read on.
"Tony Stark not...
"Not recommended"?
That doesn't make any sense.
How can you approve me
but not approve me?
I got a new ticker.
(STAMMERING)
I'm trying to do right by Pepper.
I'm in a stable-ish relationship.
Which leads us to believe
at this juncture
we'd only like to use you
as a consultant.
You can't afford me.
Then again,
I will waive my customary retainer
in exchange for a small favor.
Rhodey and I are being honored
in Washington and we need a presenter.
I'll see what I can do.
(HIGHWAY TO HELL PLAYING)
It is my honor to be here today
to present these distinguished awards
to Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes
and Mr. Tony Stark,
who is, of course, a national treasure.
Thank you, Lieutenant Colonel,
for such an exceptionally
distinguished performance.
- You deserve this.
- Thank you, sir.
Mr. Stark. Thank you
for such an exceptionally
distinguished performance.
You deserve this.
Ow!
Oh, sorry.
Funny how annoying
a little prick can be, isn't it?
Let's get a photo.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(MAKE WAY FOR TOMORROW
TODAY PLAYING)
Sir, we've found it.